think of the acquisition of of Taylor
Mcgra and what can he do for you guys?
What does he add to your quarterback
record?
>> I just think uh at that point in the
draft
and again I think Andrew can speak to
this more than I can but you're looking
for players that have traits, elite
traits, which he has something you think
you can work with and give yourself a
chance to develop.
um you hear some great things from not
only when he was at Boise or Arkansas
terms of how he's wired and uh so we're
just looking forward to get to work with
him. I know you said that I know you
previously said that like uh holding
like a a four-way quarterback
competition isn't ideal and andrew kind
of uh indicated that he needs some
polish for this game, but um do you feel
comfortable with like the plan going
forward to to not only hold this
quarterback competition, but to get all
the quarterbacks the reps that they need
uh the young ones to develop?
>> Well, let's just talk about what
competition means at every position.
every player that's going to be a part
of our roster is going to be competing,
right? I mean, whoever we bring in, uh,
starting with rookie mini camp and then
OTAAS's mandatory mini camp and then
training camp, but as we've spoken
before at any position, that doesn't
mean equal reps.
>> I mean, there there has to be some form
of a a depth chart, per se. Uh,
everybody has a chance to compete. Uh,
they just they're not always going to
get equal reps, if that makes sense. You
know, it's what is a competition? Every
guy that's in training camp, every guy
that's part of a roster, the amount of
reps they get, uh, that's to be
determined.
>> How how playing the last couple of years
for Taylor playing the last couple years
under Bob in Bobby's system, how has
that sort of gotten him prepared for
this level in terms of what what he does
schematically, what he asks his
quarterbacks to do within that system?
Well, first off,
coach did a great job of adapting.
Um, which really good coordinators do.
They adapted. You know, if you look at
quarterbacks that coach Petrino's had in
the past compared to to this young man,
different um they did a great job of
adapting to his strengths and you can
see that. But I I'm sure there were
still still core principles of the
expectations that he has for their
quarterbacks. And you could see the
development over the few the few years,
you know, from when he was at Boise.
Really developed as a passer. You can
you can see that. Always has been able
to run and and
you can see that in his statistics. You
can see when he was at Boise
how few of times they threw it compared
to where they were at Arkansas, how they
felt more comfortable uh with his
ability to throw the football down the
field.
>> Todd, with with Talon, uh Andrew made it
clear that you guys view him as a
quarterback first, but as as your
offensive mind that you are, do you sort
of envision or what are some of the
other ways that you feel like maybe you
can get him involved and get the ball in
his hands given the skill set that you
highlighted?
Well, that remains to be determined. I
will say say this that it is very
difficult to be elite at one position in
the NFL, let alone two.
I think uh teams are starting to find
that out.
>> With obviously your long time reputation
as a as a really good quarterback,
tutor, guru, uh how much how eager are
you to get your hands on a on a
quarterback like this with such raw
physical ability and just almost kind of
like mold him into like whatever he can
kind of be.
>> Well,
I mean it's uh we're excited about any
player that we get. Uh
so so be to be able to get I I wouldn't
just single out him per se other than
we're excited with his skill set and
coach but Jakeian's excited uh to add
someone with his traits that we're
hopeful to be able to get, you know, on
the field and then see what we got.
>> Look at um your offense now, the players
you have now compared to when the draft
started. Do you see how your playbook
could open up more with especially the
two receivers you got?
>> Not yet.
Haven't seen them yet. We'll have a
better idea once they get here. Am I
excited? Yes, I'm excited about uh the
work that Andrew has done thus far. We
have another pick left and and his
staff. Um I think it's been a great
draft, but what matters is now once they
get here. Um, and then how we develop
them and how we uh put them in the right
places to let their talent shine.
>> Your approach specifically to player
development across the board. This draft
feels like so many of these guys have a
lot of versatility. How does that play
into your approach when you're looking
to develop a young player when they have
played multiple positions when they have
that versatility as one of their skill
sets that they're praised about?
Well, I think
a huge strength of a player is
versatility
and it's going to happen that way in the
draft. Andrew and I were talking about
that in the draft room of why certain
linemen go higher in the draft than
others. Is it a center only? Is it a
guard only? Um, is it a tackle? We don't
see their body type as a guard.
Obviously, tackles are going to go
sooner. Uh, versatile wise, versatility
wise. Is it a a wide tight end that can
block and also attack you vertically and
separate? So, all of that comes into
play.
But until we get those players here and
get a chance to work with them, um I
don't know that yet. But we are excited
about what we've seen on film and the
anticipation that we can we can move
them and have some some flexibility in
the spots that they play. So,
>> Taylor, just you talked about the rare
traits and so did Andrew. Um, how extra
rare maybe to see from a guy that size,
you know, ID is more close to 66.
>> Well,
you're exactly right because those guys
are playing basketball.
I mean, that's that's you're seeing them
on the basketball court. You're you're
not seeing them play football or at
least not at that position. um you'll
see some taller wide outs that you'll
get, but at quarterback uh you don't see
that very often for sure.
>> You guys have three obviously very young
quarterbacks now uh that you're going to
be working on developing
and and last year these guys had to do
two spotting in practice and some
different things. Do you think that that
will make it, you know, kind of easier
on and you guys as a staff knowing that
they had to kind of do that last year
and will you do some of that? Will you
try some two spotting and whatnot to get
these guys up to speed?
>> Oh yeah, two spotting isn't new. I mean,
it's and it's not just for the
quarterbacks. It's for all of your
players. Toughest part is you have to
divide up the staff. Your staff has to
be willing to understand that you're not
going to when you're territorial as a
coach like you're going to have to allow
the strength of our staff to split up
and allow our guys to get reps. So
ultimately um we'll end up two spotting
and having you know number of
quarterbacks helps that. But I'm excited
for all the players on our roster be
able to spot and evaluate every single
one of them.
Parker. Um, Andrew mentioned how he
thinks he's a perfect fit with your
scheme. What is it about his skill set
that matches what you want from that
center position?
>> Well, you'd prefer a center with
elite athleticism, but enough size and
power to not get overwhelmed inside.
Now, that's in a perfect world,
obviously. Who doesn't want big, fast,
smart, tough at every position?
Obviously, um when you watch him on
tape,
you would not see the size deficiency.
You'd see an athletic, powerful, use his
hands well against the best competition
uh that you can find in college
football. So, we were ecstatic when he
was there when we were able to pick and
we had him here for, you know, our 30
visit. And I know coach Warhop is
excited about not only him, but all
three of the of the guys that we've got
uh that'll be here in a week in a week.
Well, no, two weeks. And we go we go two
weeks later.
91. I know we talked to you after the
the um the first pay. We didn't talk to
you after KC was taken. Um how much of
coming from Baltimore like of Z Flowers
do you kind of see in him in terms of
the role that he might have in this
offense?
Well, first of all, I love Zay Flowers.
He is an elite elite player
and an unbelievable person and and works
awfully hard at it. And from the moment
he got there, he popped the way he
played, his personality, his charisma,
you know, he brings some to the table. I
don't know yet what KC's skill set. I I
think there's some traits there that are
similar to that.
But I loved when people
spoke about KC. It reminded me of Zay in
that
in terms of how he practiced, what he
brings it every day. And that if you're
looking for that comparison that I I can
compare that that I I believe he's going
to bring that like like Zay did.
>> What do you got? Could you see could you
see getting like a I know we're putting
the horse maybe a little bit but with
somebody that has that kind of you know
he's rushed for touch what could you put
a package in at some point during the
season and try to utilize some of that
raw athletic ability that he has for
converting fourth down
>> I think there's there's some of that
remains to be seen certainly
when you have a player with those kind
of traits
when can you utilize ize those obvious
reasons. Short yardage, goal line, four
minute, critical times when you got to
be able to run the ball and the defense
is going to have an extra element in the
box. Having an athletic quarterback can
be critical to having success. So, if
he's able to do that, then
we'll certainly put him in a position if
we think that can help us win a game. I
mean, for sure because it certainly adds
some value with his ability to throw it
compared when you get in those
situations as opposed to having to go
Wildcat.
It's not that Q can't throw it, but I
would doubt he can throw it as well as
the young man we just took. I probably
can't run it like Q can, but having the
ability to still throw it and that
that's part of the intrigue when you
take a player with those kind of traits
when they start off as what can they do
for athletically and then how can you
develop the other parts of their game.